

CONTACT

- **(**+94) 71 919 0880
- ☑ dilanthaweerakoon@gmail.com
- No.93/1, Kandy Road, Yakkala
- in <u>www.linkedin.com/in/wihanga</u> <u>-dilantha</u>
- github.com/wihanga-dilantha

EDUCATION

 UNIVERSITY OF RUHUNA SRI LANKA
FACULTY OF TECHNOLOGY
Bachelor of Information and Communication Technology (Honors) - (Jan 2019 - Dec 2023)
GPA: 3.18/4.00

CERTIFICATED COURSES

- Microservices with Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Docker, K8s -Udemy
- React Native The Practical Guide - Udemy
- Introduction to Data Science -Cisco Networking Academy
- Career Essentials in Generative Al by Microsoft and LinkedIn -Microsoft

WIHANGA DILANTHA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

A passionate software engineer with over one year of experience in Java, Spring Boot and Microservices, specializing in backend development and REST APIs. Additionally, I have over a year of experience in React, Python and Flask. I excel at problem-solving, system design, and system enhancement. As a responsible and self-motivated individual, I am a recent graduate with strong technical skills, eager to embrace challenges, and dedicated to utilizing my abilities to contribute to organizational growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Virtusa (Pvt) Ltd | Colombo 9 Software Engineer Intern

2023 MAY - PRESENT

Project: Enterprise Application Group, Virtusa Internal ERP system

- I contributed to developing and maintaining RESTful APIs using Java and Spring Boot Microservices architecture and deployed in MS Azure.
- I contributed to improving the performance and scalability of the CheckIn web application by optimizing microservices communication and data handling.
- I have taken on the responsibility of implementing some features and functionalities to enhance user experience with **React**.
- I have worked with a large-scale database, ensuring data integrity and efficient data retrieval using **Oracle SQL** and **PL/SQL**.
- I have developed comprehensive DataLake reports in MS Azure Synapse and Analytics to support business decision-making processes.
- I utilized **PySpark** for writing efficient queries to process real-time, large-scale data in **Azure DataLake** to gain actionable insights.
- I added pipelining and scheduling for DataLake reports to ensure timely and automated data processing. I conducted QA releases, addressed defects, and contributed to production deployment.
- I have utilized **MS Power BI** to create interactive and visually compelling dashboards and reports.
- I have integrated data from the CheckIn web application into Azure Logic Apps, ensuring seamless data flow and synchronization.
- I have developed subscribers in Azure Logic Apps for efficient data retrieval and processing while managing deployment processes and addressing defects to maintain functionality and reliability.
- I have effectively communicated with the cross-functional teams, QA team, and Project managers by ensuring a collaborative and smooth workflow in an Agile working environment.
- This experience has deepened my understanding of the complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), spanning from inception to deployment and maintenance.

EXTRA -CURRICULAR **ACTIVITIES**

- Captain of Faculty Chess Team (Aug 2021 - Mar 2023) University of Ruhuna
- Secretary of Faculty Sports Club (Jan 2021 - Dec 2022) University of Ruhuna
- International Rated Chess Player - FIDE
- Arbiter Chess Federation Sri Lanka
- · Certified Chess Instructor -Chess Federation Sri Lanka

LANGUAGES

- Sinhala (Native)
- English (Proficient)

NON- RELATED REFEREES

Dr. P. K. S. C. Jayasinghe, Head of the Department, Senior Lecturer, Department of ICT, Faculty of Technology, University of Ruhuna. Email: subash@ictec.ruh.ac.lk Phone: (+94) 71 405 1398

R.D.N. Shakya, Lecturer (Probationary), Department of ICT, Faculty of Technology, University of Ruhuna. Email: shakya@ictec.ruh.ac.lk Phone: (+94) 77 493 5648

SKILLS

- Java
- Python
- C
- **Spring Boot**
- Microservices
- Hibernate
- **Spring Cloud**
- Spring MVC
- Spring Security •
- Junit
- **Tomcat**
- **RESTful API**
- CI/CD (Jenkins) Linux
- **Containers** (Docker)
- Container Orchestration (Kubernetes)
- **Build Tools**

- HTML
- **CSS**
- **JavaScript**
- TypeScript
- Flask
- Firebase
 - **Firebase**
 - authentication •
 - Firebase Realtime
 - **Database**
 - Azure Cloud
- PHP
- Laravel

Bootstrap Material-UI

React

Node.js

Next.js **Android**

CNN

LSTM

MySQL

ΑI

TensorFlow

PostgreSQL

Tailwind CSS

React Native

- PL/SQL **PySpark**
 - Agile
 - Version Control (git)
 - Google Colab
 - Azure DevOps

Oracle SQL

- Jira
- Time management
- Critical thinking
- Communication skills
- Adaptability
- **Team working**

PROJECTS

Al-Powered Chess Position Analysis and Move Prediction System

Developed a chess position analysis and move prediction system utilizing a CNN model with TensorFlow. Trained the model on Google Colab and designed a user-friendly interface using Bootstrap and Flask for seamless interaction.

(CNN | Deep Learning | TensorFlow | Flask)

• Al Powered Speech Emotion Detection System

Developed a system capable of detecting human emotions from voice inputs, employing a custom LSTM model trained using TensorFlow. Utilized Google Colab for model training and integration with user interfaces designed using Bootstrap and Flask technologies.

(LSTM | Deep Learning | TensorFlow | Flask)

Modern Portfolio Website

A responsive portfolio website has been developed based on a client's requirements to showcase their skills and experiences effectively.

(React | Next.js | TypeScript | Tailwind CSS)

Gas Level Indicator Application

Developed an Android application to monitor domestic gas cylinder levels and detect gas leaks in real-time, utilizing IoT devices for live data transfer. Built with React Native and integrated with Google Firebase Realtime Database.

(React Native | Firebase)

RMD Food City Ecommerce Platform

Designed and developed the RMD Food City Ecommerce Platform using React JS and Laravel, offering a user-friendly interface and advanced functionalities for a seamless online shopping experience.

(React Native | Laravel)